A Guide to the Falmouth, Jamaica Field Surveys and Drawings
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Falmouth, Jamaica Field Surveys and Drawings
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
14633-a
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the Special Collections Library by Louis Nelson, Department of Architectural History, University of Virginia in May 2010.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of the University of Virginia Historic Preservation Field School in Falmouth, Jamaica, ca. 2008, directed by Louis Nelson, School of Architecture, consists of 25 three-ring binders of field notes for the Falmouth Small Buildings Survey and about fifty-three drawings, ca. 150 items (5 boxes, 2 linear feet) total. In each binder, there were several surveys from blocks that consist mostly of forms and colored paper dividing each block. These have been removed from the binders and placed in folders by block numbers.
Arrangement
Papers are organized in two series: Series I: Field Surveys from Binders (Boxes 1-5) and Series II: Architectural Drawings (2 Oversize folders)
Contents List
- Series I: Field Surveys from Binders
  - n.d. Falmouth, Jamaica, Field Surveys Falmouth Historic District, including: B004, B009, B015, B023, B024, and B052 (1 of 3). (Box-folder 1:1)
  - n.d. Falmouth, Jamaica, Field Surveys Falmouth Historic District, including: B004, B009, B015, B023, B024, and B052 (2 of 3). (Box-folder 1:2)
  - n.d. Falmouth, Jamaica, Field Surveys Falmouth Historic District, including: B004, B009, B015, B023, B024, and B052 (3 of 3). (Box-folder 1:3)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 1 - 10 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 2 and 3 - 30 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 4, 9, and 15 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 5, 7, and 8-14 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 10, 11, and 12-35 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 13 and 14 -30 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 19 and 20 -30 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 22 and 55 -24 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 21 - 25 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 28 and 56 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 29 and 41 -17 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 30 - 25 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 31 and 66 -28 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 32, 33, and 34 (1 of 2) (Box-folder 2:8)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 32, 33, and 34 (2 of 2) (Box-folder 2:9)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 38 and 39 -16 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 42 - 27 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 43 - 25 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 44 - 30 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 45 - 24 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 46 and 47 -40 and 50 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 46 and 47 -40 and 50 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 48 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 49 - 40 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 51 - 25 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 53 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 54 and 57 -30 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 58 - 28 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 59 - 40 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 60 - 35 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 61 - 37 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 62 - 50 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 62 - 50 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 63 and 64 -30 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 65 and 73 -25 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 67 - 27 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 68 and 69 -22 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 71 - 30 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - 2008 Falmouth, Jamaica-Block 70 and 72 -23 (Box-folder 5:9)
- Series II: Architectural Drawings
  - 2004-2009 Sketches on graph paper include the following buildings:, (35 sheets) (Oversize Folder 1)
    Albert George Arcade, Side Elevation, Details of Column and Gate, and Front of Building with the Clock Tower in the Center; Baptist Manse, FHR Headquarters, Market Street Elevation; Bunker Hill Unity; Colbeck NW Outbuilding; Colbeck SE Outbuilding; Falmouth All Ages School Site Plan; Falmouth Post Office North Elevation; Falmouth Waterwheel; Falmouth United Church East Elevation, North Elevation, and Church View Duke Street; Good Hope Office Ground Floor and Upper Floor Plans; Good Hope Warehouse Front Elevation; Industrial Yard Site Plan; Sammy's Water Square; St. Joseph Catholic Church North Elevation; 7 Upper Harbour Street North Elevation, [Floor Plan], East Elevation, First Floor Plan; 29 Cornwall Street; and 37 Market Street Front Elevation
  - 2008-2009 Measured drawings on heavy [translucent ?] paper and one on graph paper include the following buildings: Albert George Arcade; Baptist Manse, FHR Headquarters, Market Street Elevation; Falmouth Post Office North Elevation; Falmouth Water Wheel; Fort Balcarre, now Falmouth All - Ages School on both translucent and graph paper; St. Joseph Catholic Church [Floor Plan]; Unity Church, Trelawney Parish and Falmouth United Church (possibly the same building?); 7 Upper Harbour Street, North Elevation, [Floor Plan], and East Elevation; Some drawings were made on paper which has a note to credit the Historic American Buildings Survey (HABS) and the National Park Service on the sheets, (18 sheets) (Oversize Folder 2)